<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Supreme Commander 2 on Forged Defiance</title>
    <link>/tags/supreme-commander-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Supreme Commander 2 on Forged Defiance</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/supreme-commander-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Supreme Commander 2 Hidden Objectives List</title>
      <link>/post/supreme-commander-2-hidden-objectives-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/supreme-commander-2-hidden-objectives-list/</guid>
      <description> Update 2010-03-26: Missed &amp;ldquo;Master of Pawns&amp;rdquo; hidden objective off of Cybran mission 6. Added it.
Trying to find and complete all the secret missions in SupCom 2? Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick and dirty list of them all!
This information is copied from the map files within the SupCom 2 directory.
Feel free to copy and paste — a link back to this page would be appreciated!
The List UEF  1 – Prime Target  Survivor  Survive the initial wave of Cybran attackers without losing any units.   2 – Off Base  Economic Opportunist  Build at least two Mass Extractors in enemy territory.   3 – Strike While Cold  Master of the Seas  Build an Atlantis II Experimental Aircraft Carrier.   4 – Titans of Industry  Brutal Conqueror  Defeat Coleman without the aid of the Fatboys.   5 – Factions or Family Plan  Experimenter  Build at least four Experimental units   6 – End of an Alliance  Nuke King  Launch your first nuke.  None Shall Pass!  Prevent any enemy King Kriptors from crossing the main fortress bridge.    Illuminate  1 – Delta Force  Blockhead  Prevent the blockade from taking more than 25% damage.   2 – Lethal Weapons  Master Tactician  Complete the operation by constructing fewer than 30 mobile units.   3 – Back on the Chain Gang  Not the Bees!  You have successfully taken over the enemy air defenses.  Pro Anti-Air  You have successfully taken over the prison&amp;rsquo;s defensive structures.  Agent Provocateur  Capture all of the Security Stations.   4 – Steamed  Experimental Fanatic  Build at least eight Experimental units.   5 – Cliff Diving  Supremest Commander  Reach the highest level of veterancy with your ACU.   6 – Prime Time  Bot Lord  Complete the operation with an army made up entirely of Assault Bots.  A Czar is Born  Build your first Darkenoid.    Cybran  1 – Fact Finder  Survival Expert  Survive Gauge&amp;rsquo;s onslaught after the download completes.   2 – The Trouble With Technology  Master Thief  Capture a Rogue Engineer.  Great Escapist  Complete the operation without a unit being captured by the enemy.   3 – The Great Leap Forward  Cache and Carry  Collect all of the Technology Caches.   4 – Gatekeeper  Sultan of Soul  Build at least four Soul Ripper Experimentals.   5 – Surface Tension  Master of the Deep  Build a Kraken Experimental Submarine.   6 – The Final Countdown  Research Savant  Complete all available research.  Master of Pawns  Win the operation without the aid of any Experimentals.    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>