<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Windows on Forged Defiance</title>
    <link>/categories/windows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Windows on Forged Defiance</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Larger tab close buttons in Firefox</title>
      <link>/post/larger-tab-close-buttons-in-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/larger-tab-close-buttons-in-firefox/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m using a Windows 8 tablet (the Linx 10 if you&amp;rsquo;re curious) and found that the close buttons in Firefox were a bit small and difficult to press.
I&amp;rsquo;ve fixed this by adding the following to my userChrome.css file:
{% highlight css %} .tab-close-button { border-radius: 20%; background: rgba(0,0,0,0.1) !important; width: 32px !important; height: 32px !important; } {% endhighlight %}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A fix for VirtualBox causing Windows host to think it&#39;s on a public network</title>
      <link>/post/a-fix-for-virtualbox-causing-host-windows-to-think-its-on-a-public-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/a-fix-for-virtualbox-causing-host-windows-to-think-its-on-a-public-network/</guid>
      <description>Have a look at Brokenwire.NET&amp;rsquo;s article on the subject.
I&amp;rsquo;ll briefly mirror the instructions here:
 Open regedit. Search (Ctrl+F) for VirtualBox Host-Only Ethernet Adapter. Keep searching until you&amp;rsquo;re inside HKLM\SYSTEM\CurrentControlSet\Control\Class\{4D36E972-E325-11CE-BFC1-08002BE10318} &amp;mdash; you&amp;rsquo;ll probably be highlighting the DriverDesc key. Add/modify a DWORD value, called NdisDeviceType, and give it a value of 1. Restart the machine.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop Exact Audio Copy Crashing on Windows 7</title>
      <link>/post/stop-exact-audio-copy-crashing-on-windows-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/stop-exact-audio-copy-crashing-on-windows-7/</guid>
      <description>When I tried to rip a disc using Exact Audio Copy on Windows 7 x64, I found it kept crashing as soon as the rip tried to start. Bummer.
Remembering the previous times I&amp;rsquo;ve used EAC, when you click a button to start a rip, it asks you where you want to save the ripped files.
Turns out if you set EAC to save into a predetermined location instead of asking, EAC manages to rip perfectly fine!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Windows 7 Taskbar — Keyboard Goodness</title>
      <link>/post/the-windows-7-taskbar-keyboard-goodness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-windows-7-taskbar-keyboard-goodness/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re fortunate enough to be using Windows 7, then no doubt you&amp;rsquo;ve noticed the new taskbar. Well, here&amp;rsquo;s a couple of golden nuggets of info for you:
Did you know that all the icons you line up on the taskbar automatically get keyboard shortcuts? If you want to launch one of them, just press the Windows key and the number of the program&amp;rsquo;s position along the list. So to launch the first program, press Win+1; to launch the second, press Win+2; this continues all the way up to Win+0, which opens the tenth program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Word of Warning: Check Your Windows 7 Backup Settings</title>
      <link>/post/a-word-of-warning-check-your-windows-7-backup-settings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/a-word-of-warning-check-your-windows-7-backup-settings/</guid>
      <description>Backups in Windows 7 have been greatly improved, what with the fact you can restore from them (without needing to take a separate backup) and that they backup to networks better.
However, there has been one change which caught me out, thanks to a subtle and ambiguous rewording of the backups dialog.
When backups are taken, as default only user folders that were created by Windows are backed up. For reference that&amp;rsquo;s Appdata, Contacts, Desktop, Downloads, Favorites, Links, Music, Pictures, Saved Games, Searches and Videos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding your most recent Twitter tweet to your Pidgin status</title>
      <link>/post/adding-your-most-recent-twitter-tweet-to-your-pidgin-status/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/adding-your-most-recent-twitter-tweet-to-your-pidgin-status/</guid>
      <description>This guide is intended to be a more up-to-date mirror of the guide you can find at Tech Jawa. All credit to them for the original instructions! Basically nothing changes, but I just like to be comprehensive.
 Download the TwitterStatus plugin. It&amp;rsquo;ll be a file ending in .pl. Move this file to your Pidgin plugins folder. If any folders don&amp;rsquo;t exist, create them:  Linux: ~/.purple/plugins/ Windows Vista/7: C:\Users&amp;lt;Username&amp;gt;\AppData\Roaming.purple\plugins  Install Perl:  Linux: It&amp;rsquo;s probably already installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ogg Vorbis Encoder for Windows</title>
      <link>/post/ogg-vorbis-encoder-for-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ogg-vorbis-encoder-for-windows/</guid>
      <description>I not so long ago made a post about using Ogg Vorbis for Ringtones on Android, as it considerably reduces the lag between getting a phone call and the phone actually playing the ringtone. The same goes for music on the device–it just starts playing quicker.
Anyway, just now I realised that I didn&amp;rsquo;t link to any encoders for it. So if anyone wondered what I used to accomplish the task, they&amp;rsquo;d be stuck!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quickly Open an Elevated Command Prompt in Vista</title>
      <link>/post/quickly-open-an-elevated-command-prompt-in-vista/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/quickly-open-an-elevated-command-prompt-in-vista/</guid>
      <description>Just a quick little thing I noticed, although everyone else probably knows it by now.
To launch an elevated command prompt (i.e. a prompt with admin privileges, required to do various things if UAC is enabled on Vista), simply open the Start Menu (Windows key), type &amp;ldquo;cmd&amp;rdquo; without quotes, and press Control+Shift+Return.
This will bring up a UAC prompt asking you to elevate the process. Select Continue (Alt+C). Done!
This does work for some other applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ll Modify You in to Next Week.</title>
      <link>/post/ill-modify-you-in-to-next-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ill-modify-you-in-to-next-week/</guid>
      <description>A couple of days ago I came across this interesting quirk, and I had to do a double-take before I realised what had happened.
Basically, I recently got a NAS and decided that I wanted my router to save its bandwidth usage statistics on it. That way whenever I perform an upgrade to the firmware on the router I won&amp;rsquo;t erase all the stats. This part is easy, as the firmware has the functionality for this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix Windows Sidebar Gadget File Association in Vista</title>
      <link>/post/fix-windows-sidebar-gadget-file-association-in-vista/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/fix-windows-sidebar-gadget-file-association-in-vista/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever somehow managed to break the Gadget file association in Windows Vista? I have somehow, and that means that you can no longer install gadgets. Double-clicking a .gadget file does nothing, and the Sidebar offers no option to install gadgets itself!
If you try to re-associate the files with Windows Sidebar by telling to Open With… and navigating to the Sidebar executable, you&amp;rsquo;ll have found that that doesn&amp;rsquo;t help — all it does is bring the Sidebar to focus, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t install the gadget.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>