<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Itunes on Forged Defiance</title>
    <link>/categories/itunes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Itunes on Forged Defiance</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/itunes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Delete Songs From Smart Playlists in iTunes</title>
      <link>/post/delete-songs-from-smart-playlists-in-itunes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/delete-songs-from-smart-playlists-in-itunes/</guid>
      <description>Update 2009-11-23: Corrected Mac keyboard keys. I don&amp;rsquo;t own a Mac myself, but a friend of mine tells me that iTunes defies the normal behaviour of many other Apple applications. Probably because it&amp;rsquo;s ancient and desperately needs an update.
Made a smart playlist to find songs you want to delete, then found that the delete function no longer works?
Just hold Shift. Or Option.
Pressing Shift+Delete on Windows or Option+Delete on Mac will give you a prompt to delete songs just like any other delete operation performed in the library.
Holding Shift on Windows or Option on Mac and right-clicking on one or more songs will show &amp;ldquo;Delete&amp;rdquo; in the context menu.
As an aside, this shortcut also allows you to delete songs from static playlists as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reset iTunes Dimensions to Fit Resolution</title>
      <link>/post/reset-itunes-dimensions-to-fit-resolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/reset-itunes-dimensions-to-fit-resolution/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a handy little feature that I find useful. If you ever play around with the size or location of the iTunes window and want to make it fit the screen better, simply follow the instructions:
 If you&amp;rsquo;re on Windows: hold Shift and either double-click the title bar or single-click the maximise button (The title bar is the small bar at the top that says &amp;ldquo;iTunes&amp;rdquo; in the middle.) If you&amp;rsquo;re on Mac OS: hold Option and click the Zoom (+) button  This&amp;rsquo;ll reset the size and position to its default for your screen resolution. Assuming you haven&amp;rsquo;t changed screen resolution since installing it, it&amp;rsquo;ll look just as it did when you first installed it — nearly filling the entire screen, but not quite. It&amp;rsquo;s also a very useful shortcut if you ever change your screen resolution.
Doing the operation a second time will move the iTunes window back to where it was before you started reading this article and messing with it. Simple!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>