<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Games on Forged Defiance</title>
    <link>/categories/games/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Games on Forged Defiance</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Gran Turismo 5&#39;s slow loading times</title>
      <link>/post/fixing-gran-turismo-5s-slow-loading-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/fixing-gran-turismo-5s-slow-loading-times/</guid>
      <description>Just this morning Gran Turismo 5 just out of nowhere started loading really slowly.
I fixed this by signing out of PSN. It&amp;rsquo;s not ideal if you want to play online, but it&amp;rsquo;s worked for me.
It should be noted that the problem can been seen from the XMB before you even launch the game – just after it displays the message that you&amp;rsquo;ve &amp;ldquo;signed in&amp;rdquo;, watch the clock and see how long it spins; this is the console synchronizing the time with PSN. If this takes more than a couple of seconds, there might be a problem.
In addition, check your friends list. If it seems significantly shorter, and each friend is only very slowly appearing one at once, you can count on having troubles launching GT5.
Finally, note that when you launch GT5 without being connected, the points where the game hangs are the points it asks you if you want to connect to PSN.
I can only assume that this is a PSN issue because I can confirm on my Tomato router that my connection is entirely utilised. Of course, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t guarantee the problem isn&amp;rsquo;t my end…
If your loading problem isn&amp;rsquo;t thanks to PSN or a slow internet connection, then it might be that it isn&amp;rsquo;t installed, the HDD is dying, the disc is scratched, the Blu-ray is dying… All the usual suspects really.
Good luck!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supreme Commander 2 Hidden Objectives List</title>
      <link>/post/supreme-commander-2-hidden-objectives-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/supreme-commander-2-hidden-objectives-list/</guid>
      <description> Update 2010-03-26: Missed &amp;ldquo;Master of Pawns&amp;rdquo; hidden objective off of Cybran mission 6. Added it.
Trying to find and complete all the secret missions in SupCom 2? Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick and dirty list of them all!
This information is copied from the map files within the SupCom 2 directory.
Feel free to copy and paste — a link back to this page would be appreciated!
The List UEF  1 – Prime Target  Survivor  Survive the initial wave of Cybran attackers without losing any units.   2 – Off Base  Economic Opportunist  Build at least two Mass Extractors in enemy territory.   3 – Strike While Cold  Master of the Seas  Build an Atlantis II Experimental Aircraft Carrier.   4 – Titans of Industry  Brutal Conqueror  Defeat Coleman without the aid of the Fatboys.   5 – Factions or Family Plan  Experimenter  Build at least four Experimental units   6 – End of an Alliance  Nuke King  Launch your first nuke.  None Shall Pass!  Prevent any enemy King Kriptors from crossing the main fortress bridge.    Illuminate  1 – Delta Force  Blockhead  Prevent the blockade from taking more than 25% damage.   2 – Lethal Weapons  Master Tactician  Complete the operation by constructing fewer than 30 mobile units.   3 – Back on the Chain Gang  Not the Bees!  You have successfully taken over the enemy air defenses.  Pro Anti-Air  You have successfully taken over the prison&amp;rsquo;s defensive structures.  Agent Provocateur  Capture all of the Security Stations.   4 – Steamed  Experimental Fanatic  Build at least eight Experimental units.   5 – Cliff Diving  Supremest Commander  Reach the highest level of veterancy with your ACU.   6 – Prime Time  Bot Lord  Complete the operation with an army made up entirely of Assault Bots.  A Czar is Born  Build your first Darkenoid.    Cybran  1 – Fact Finder  Survival Expert  Survive Gauge&amp;rsquo;s onslaught after the download completes.   2 – The Trouble With Technology  Master Thief  Capture a Rogue Engineer.  Great Escapist  Complete the operation without a unit being captured by the enemy.   3 – The Great Leap Forward  Cache and Carry  Collect all of the Technology Caches.   4 – Gatekeeper  Sultan of Soul  Build at least four Soul Ripper Experimentals.   5 – Surface Tension  Master of the Deep  Build a Kraken Experimental Submarine.   6 – The Final Countdown  Research Savant  Complete all available research.  Master of Pawns  Win the operation without the aid of any Experimentals.    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phoenix Wright — Ace Attorney: Trials and Tribulations Soundtrack Download</title>
      <link>/post/phoenix-wright-ace-attorney-trials-and-tribulations-soundtrack-download/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/phoenix-wright-ace-attorney-trials-and-tribulations-soundtrack-download/</guid>
      <description>That was a mouthful of a title.
Over time I&amp;rsquo;ve played and thoroughly enjoyed the Ace Attorney series of games, from Phoenix Wright to Apollo Justice. But for those of you familiar to the series, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice that this is the soundtrack for the third game in the series. So why have I posted this one?
You see, this soundtrack posting has a small story behind it. A while back a perfectionist of a soundtrack ripper called TheRedPriest ripped the soundtrack and uploaded it to his website. He gets wound up by pops and blips in tracks — I can relate to that…
Anyway, unfortunately like so many good things on the web, the website went offline! Luckily, a member of the forum called GUI uploaded the soundtrack and all was good within the world.
Since I hate having just one mirror for things that have had so much time and effort put into them, and because I like the soundtrack so much, I decided to host the soundtrack for myself.
Just to make it clear: I did not rip this soundtrack or have any input in its ripping! I am but a simple mirror, wanting to preserve the great work of a video game soundtrack ripper.
Hope that everyone enjoys this as much as I do.
Download the Phoenix Wright — Ace Attorney: Trials and Tribulations soundtrack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advance Wars 2 Soundtrack Download</title>
      <link>/post/advance-wars-2-soundtrack-download/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/advance-wars-2-soundtrack-download/</guid>
      <description>Andy, a Commanding Officer from Advance Wars 2  Ah, Advance Wars 2. What is it about you I thought was so amazing? The lovable, single-minded cast? The deep turn-based strategy? The little battle animations of infantry flying off the screen?
Well, okay, all of those things are very good reasons to love the game, but there&amp;rsquo;s another one that sticks out for me too.
The soundtrack!
Once I completed the normal campaign and could buy the Sound Room, that was it. Time and again I&amp;rsquo;ve inserted the cart into my GBA purely for the reason of enjoying the music on an infinite loop.
Yes, I am that way inclined as a person, but there&amp;rsquo;s something about this soundtrack that keeps me coming back. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if it&amp;rsquo;s the enthusiastic beats or the simple, catchy tunes, but this is one soundtrack I struggle to put down.
But anyway, enough of me rambling about game soundtracks; judge for yourself! Ripped by yours truly and packaged as 192kbps MP3s, the Advance Wars 2 soundtrack is one you should definitely have in your library if you enjoy the game or the kind of music you get from a GBA.
Download the Advance Wars 2 Soundtrack.
Also available from another site I co-run, Black Hole Headquarters.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>