<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Download on Forged Defiance</title>
    <link>/categories/download/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Download on Forged Defiance</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/download/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Searchlight 1.6</title>
      <link>/post/searchlight-1-6-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/searchlight-1-6-2/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve released another update to Searchlight!
This one contains some experimental code for devices that use the CyanogenMod SysFS interface to toggle their light. Naturally, given it&amp;rsquo;s experimental, it might not work. :-) That&amp;rsquo;s because I don&amp;rsquo;t have any devices that actually make use of it.
Get in touch via Google Play or the contact page if you have problems, or just want to give me a good word!
As always, you can download the update via Google Play or directly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searchlight 1.5</title>
      <link>/post/searchlight-1-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/searchlight-1-5/</guid>
      <description>Looks like I forgot to write about this when I released it in February, but Searchlight 1.5 is out!
The big thing this update adds is a widget that can be added to your launcher or to your lock screen on 4.2+ devices. That means you can toggle the light without unlocking the device!
As always you can download it from Google Play and directly from this site.
Also, for the sake of completeness, since I never got around to writing about version 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searchlight 1.1 released</title>
      <link>/post/searchlight-1-1-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/searchlight-1-1-released/</guid>
      <description>Searchlight, my application for lighting up your world (or at least a few metres in front of you) using your Android device&amp;rsquo;s LED has been updated to 1.1.
This update brings better behaviour on HTC Sense devices, where the screen is kept on (as this is necessary to keep the device&amp;rsquo;s light switched on). In addition, when the screen is switched off (manually) and switched on again, it can switch on the light again; previously it didn&amp;rsquo;t switch the light back on, yet still ran the service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searchlight: An Android LED torch powered by the Search button</title>
      <link>/post/searchlight-an-android-led-torch-powered-by-the-search-button/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/searchlight-an-android-led-torch-powered-by-the-search-button/</guid>
      <description>In case there aren&amp;rsquo;t enough of them out there, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to chip in my own effort on the Android LED torch scene.
In a sort of sequel to my first Android app Torchure, I have just released Searchlight on to the Android Market.
The unique thing about this flashlight is that it&amp;rsquo;s activated by long-pressing the Search button. Each time you do this, the LED will toggle on or off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Personal Ninite Installer</title>
      <link>/post/my-personal-ninite-installer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/my-personal-ninite-installer/</guid>
      <description>This is basically for my own future reference, but the last few Windows installs I&amp;rsquo;ve done I&amp;rsquo;ve used Ninite to install most of my favourite software — easily and quickly!
If you&amp;rsquo;ve yet to discover it, check it out! Or if you&amp;rsquo;d rather just install software other people recommend wihout thinking, you can install my particular favourite software loadout.
Update 15:42 UTC+0100: Just a couple of things that I should mention about the Ninite installer:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phoenix Wright — Ace Attorney: Trials and Tribulations Soundtrack Download</title>
      <link>/post/phoenix-wright-ace-attorney-trials-and-tribulations-soundtrack-download/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/phoenix-wright-ace-attorney-trials-and-tribulations-soundtrack-download/</guid>
      <description>That was a mouthful of a title.
Over time I&amp;rsquo;ve played and thoroughly enjoyed the Ace Attorney series of games, from Phoenix Wright to Apollo Justice. But for those of you familiar to the series, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice that this is the soundtrack for the third game in the series. So why have I posted this one?
You see, this soundtrack posting has a small story behind it. A while back a perfectionist of a soundtrack ripper called TheRedPriest ripped the soundtrack and uploaded it to his website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix Windows Sidebar Gadget File Association in Vista</title>
      <link>/post/fix-windows-sidebar-gadget-file-association-in-vista/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/fix-windows-sidebar-gadget-file-association-in-vista/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever somehow managed to break the Gadget file association in Windows Vista? I have somehow, and that means that you can no longer install gadgets. Double-clicking a .gadget file does nothing, and the Sidebar offers no option to install gadgets itself!
If you try to re-associate the files with Windows Sidebar by telling to Open With… and navigating to the Sidebar executable, you&amp;rsquo;ll have found that that doesn&amp;rsquo;t help — all it does is bring the Sidebar to focus, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t install the gadget.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advance Wars 2 Soundtrack Download</title>
      <link>/post/advance-wars-2-soundtrack-download/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/advance-wars-2-soundtrack-download/</guid>
      <description>Andy, a Commanding Officer from Advance Wars 2  Ah, Advance Wars 2. What is it about you I thought was so amazing? The lovable, single-minded cast? The deep turn-based strategy? The little battle animations of infantry flying off the screen?
Well, okay, all of those things are very good reasons to love the game, but there&amp;rsquo;s another one that sticks out for me too.
The soundtrack!
Once I completed the normal campaign and could buy the Sound Room, that was it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>