<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>G1 on Forged Defiance</title>
    <link>/tags/g1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in G1 on Forged Defiance</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/g1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fix Superuser Permissions Hanging on Android</title>
      <link>/post/fix-superuser-permissions-hanging-on-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/fix-superuser-permissions-hanging-on-android/</guid>
      <description>Update 2010-03-04: Added another potential solution courtesy of Blazt in the comments. Thanks!
So, you have a phone with root permissions? Finding whenever a program requests root permissions the Superuser Permissions program hangs (usually with a black screen or even a force close) at the &amp;ldquo;SU request&amp;rdquo; screen?
Fortunately there are a couple of things you can try, which I&amp;rsquo;ll detail for you.
First, make sure USB Debugging is enabled. To do that:
 Press the Home button. Press the Menu button. Select Settings &amp;gt; Applications &amp;gt; Development. Make sure that USB Debugging is checked. If not, check it.  If that fixes your problem, you are done! If not, then you can try clearing the Superuser Permissions data. This is just any options you have set within the app and whether or not particular apps are always allowed or blocked — you won&amp;rsquo;t lose any of your other data, and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to allow/deny stuff again.
To clear the data:
 Press the Home button. Press the Menu button. Select Settings &amp;gt; Applications &amp;gt; Manage applications. Find Superuser Permissions on the list. Tap it. Tap &amp;ldquo;Clear data&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Clear cache&amp;rdquo; if they&amp;rsquo;re enabled.  This should prevent any hangs with Superuser Permissions in the future.
This works on the HTC Dream (T-Mobile G1) with the 1.5 and 1.6 firmwares, and presumably other Android devices with the Superuser Permissions app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlock Android Device Using PUK Code</title>
      <link>/post/unlock-android-device-using-puk-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/unlock-android-device-using-puk-code/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever got your PIN code wrong too many times and got your SIM locked, you were probably as surprised as I was when Android gives you no option to unlock the phone! Fortunately there&amp;rsquo;s an answer.
To unlock your Android-based device go to the Emergency Call screen and enter in the following (replace the angled brackets with the appropriate info):
**05*«PUK Code»*«Your new pin»*«Confirm your new pin»# So for example:
**05*12345678*9090*9090# As a side effect this should work on any SIM-containing device at a screen where you can enter phone numbers, not just devices running the Android OS. As of writing, Android-based devices are the HTC Dream (T-Mobile G1) and HTC Magic.
And make sure you keep your PUK code secret — anyone can override your PIN with their own using it!
Thanks to theWeir for posting that solution.
http://androidcommunity.com/forums/99706-post6.html  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>